# Roman Right (Korolev)



roman-right@protonmail.com



linkedin.com/in/roman-right

# Summary

I'm Roman, a Senior Python Developer/Team Lead with over 10 years of experience in the industry (since 2009). I have a strong passion for databases and data storage, specializing in micro/nano services, event-based systems, high-load applications, and async development. My expertise also extends to working on libraries such as ORMs and SDKs.

As a proud MongoDB Champion, I have been recognized for my expertise and contributions to the MongoDB community. Learn more about the MongoDB Champions program here: https://www.mongodb.com/community/ advocacy/

Here's what I truly enjoy:

- Designing and implementing solutions to real-life problems.
- Exploring and experimenting with the latest technologies, libraries, and frameworks.
- Sharing knowledge and insights at meetups.
- Contributing to impactful open-source projects.

I've authored the following notable projects:

Beanie: An asynchronous Python object-document mapper (ODM) for MongoDB. Check it out on GitHub: https:// github.com/roman-right/beanie

AnnaDB: A next-gen developer-first data store. Explore AnnaDB on GitHub: https://github.com/Anna-Team/ **AnnaDB** 

# **Experience**



# ot Principal Software Engineer

OneTrust

Sep 2021 - Present (1 year 11 months)

My responsibilities included:

- Designing and implementing the architecture.
- Collaborating with specialists from different domains to identify and implement effective solutions.
- Incorporating modern design patterns to enhance performance.
- Collaborating with various teams to facilitate seamless integrations.
- Taking ownership of my projects, prioritizing, and distributing tasks.

The tech stack:

- FastAPI
- MongoDB (Beanie ODM)
- Lambda Functions (Different for different cloud providers)

- Native cloud messaging systems + Kafka

# **Backend Software Engineer**

#### Teraki

Jun 2019 - Aug 2021 (2 years 3 months)

About the company:

Teraki's mission is to enable personalized and accurate machine learning based applications without a compromise towards 100% safety. It's Al-powered software product operates at the embedded level. Teraki delivers these benefits for automotive and IoT applications (such as drones, robots, smartphones) for which we lower latencies, reduce costs and enhance machine learning accuracy with 10%-30% vs. state-of-the art.

#### My duties here are:

- REST API and Kafka-based services design and implementation
- Inter-services communication design and implementation
- Databases design

# Senior Python Developer

## Twyla Al

Feb 2019 - May 2019 (4 months)

Twyla's Canvas platform enables businesses of all sizes to harness the knowledge of human subject matter experts. It provides the ability to design and implement conversational experiences that not only save time and money, but delights users.

#### **Duties:**

- Develop web services
- Design applications and databases
- API development

#### Stack:

aiohttp, flask, sanic, postgres, mongo, redis, RabbitMQ

# IT Lead

#### OSA decentralized (OSA DC)

Feb 2017 - Nov 2018 (1 year 10 months)

The company provides analytics services. Customers are large retailers and manufacturers. The service uses big data received from the retailer in real time (receipts, assortment matrix, stocks and etc. Tens of millions of records per hour)

#### **Duties:**

- System architecture design (databases and applications).
- ETL development
- Internal and external API development (REST)
- Creating microservices (Tornado, aiohttp)
- CI/CD processes
- Coordination of development team

#### Solution stack:

Python3.6, Tornado, aiohttp, Postgres, ClickHouse, Redis, Apache Spark, RabbitMQ

# IT Lead

# pplatform

Jan 2016 - Feb 2017 (1 year 2 months)

The company provides targeted advertising services. The project was implemented from scratch.

#### Duties:

- System architecture design (databases and applications).
- API development (REST)
- Creating microservices (Tornado)
- CI/CD processes
- Coordination of development team

#### Solution stack:

Python3, Tornado, Postgres, Redis

# Python developer

Mail.ru Group

Aug 2015 - Dec 2015 (5 months)

Development of health.mail.ru backend. Integration of large geo and medical services into the system.

#### **Duties:**

- API development (REST)
- Backend development (Django)
- Integrations with external services
- ETL development

#### Solution stack:

Python2.7, Django, MySQL, OSM

# **PURRAJ** Full Stack Developer

## **OORRAA**

Feb 2015 - Aug 2015 (7 months)

Prototypes development in marketplace

#### **Duties:**

- Integrations with external services
- Backend development (Django)
- Frontend development (React, Backbone)
- API development (REST)

#### Solution stack:

Python2.7, Django, Postgres, React, Backbone

# Python Developer

Jan 2009 - Feb 2015 (6 years 2 months) Development of backend and frontend

#### Duties:

- API development (REST)
- Backend development (Django, Flask)
- Frontend development (React, Backbone, Angular)
- Admin pages development
- ETL development
- CI/CD processes

# **Education**



# Lomonosov Moscow State University (MSU)

Mathematics 2007 - 2013

# **Skills**

Open-Source Development • Python • Web Development • Databases • Software Development • Project Management • Agile Methodologies • Programming • SQL • MySQL